(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
おかゆは配信を はじめようとしている！
Okayu is trying to start the stream!
バイバ～イ
Bye-bye~
長い冬がおもたい腰をあげて 春が準備をしはじめる
The long winter lifts its heavy hips, and spring begins its preparations.
大空スバル / 風真いろは
Oozora Subaru / Kazama Iroha
2月22日 そう今日は 猫の日 詰まり僕の日
February 22nd. Yes, today is Cat Day. In other words, my day.
椎名唯華 / がうる・ぐら
Shiina Yuika / Gawr Gura
今日は僕が一番偉いから おもう存分讃えてもいいよ
Today I'm the most important, so you can praise me as much as you want.
白上フブキ / 大神ミオ / 戌神ころね
Shirakami Fubuki / Ookami Mio / Inugami Korone
お、そういう感じ もっともっと頂戴
Oh, that's the spirit. Give me more, more.
紅茶に溶けたマシュマロ
Marshmallow melted in tea
僕を浮かせてバタートースト
Butter toast with me floating on top
葡萄味のアメジストキャンディ
Grape-flavored amethyst candy
やっぱ欲しいブルーベリーサンド
As expected, I want a blueberry sandwich
今年もやってきたバースデー
Birthday has come around again this year
ちょっとつまみ食いのバースデー
A birthday for a little snacking
ケーキにおにぎり刺したけど 蝋燭の代わりにはならなかった
I stuck an onigiri into the cake, but it didn't work as a candle.
あかり欲しい？ それ僕でよくない？
Need a light? Wouldn't I be enough for that?
その方が主役っぽくてよくない？
Isn't that more fitting for the main star?
そろそろ準備いい？ それじゃあカウントダウンを始めようか
Ready for this? Well then, let's start the countdown.
3, 2, 1
LIVE START!!
愛という名の 人体実験臨床
Clinical human experimentation in the name of love
私は恋するドパミン
I'm a dopamine in love
化学反応心拍数の上昇
Chemical reaction, heart rate rising
あなたに起こすの生体反応
Causing a biological reaction in you
あいしてる
I love you
天才ロック / 作詞・作曲：カラスヤサボウ
Tensai Rock / Lyrics & Composition: Karasuyasabou
サイコフィーリン頭はガンガン
Psycho-feeling, head is pounding
溢れて C8H11N
Overflowing with C8H11N
ダダダ 大嫌いから こんがらがって陽性
Da-da-da, since I hate you so much, things get tangled up and test positive
その手を握れば生体反応
If I hold your hand, it's a biological reaction
あいしてる
I love you
理科室の鍵をかけたなら
If the science lab is locked
私天才だから 天才だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius
あなたの気持ちも分かっちゃう
I understand your feelings too
あなたはだんだん私を好きになる
You'll gradually fall in love with me
天才だから 天才だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius
あなたのすべてを奪っちゃう
I'll snatch away everything about you
脳神経から感覚細胞 意識の果てまで
From cranial nerves to sensory cells, to the edge of consciousness
ハックイン・トゥー
Hack into
泣いて泣いては脳内環境散々
Crying and crying, the internal environment is a mess
求めて足りないセロトニン
Lack of serotonin, seeking more
バババグのようだね神経回路おじゃん
It's like a bug, neural circuits ruined
エンドルフィンで沸かした幸福
Happiness boiled up with endorphins
...てゆく
...as it goes.
私 天才 だから 天才 だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius,
心の在り処も分かっちゃう
I even know where the heart lies.
あなたも私もお薬の
Both you and I become
脳内物質の虜になり
captives of brain chemicals.
天才 だから 天才 だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius,
その先すべてが分かっちゃう
I understand everything beyond that.
水金地火木土天海冥
Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, Pluto,
銀河の果てまで
to the edge of the galaxy,
Dive into
嗚呼 愛も恋も
Ah, both love and romance
化学式の中の
are just an illusion
マボロシ
within a chemical formula.
ああ
Ah...
私 天才 だから 天才 だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius,
遍く全てが分かっちゃう
I understand absolutely everything.
そろそろこの世に飽きてきたころなの
I'm just about getting tired of this world.
天才 だから 天才 だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius,
あなたのその手を掴んじゃう
I'll grab that hand of yours.
屋上階から飛び出して
Jumping out from the rooftop,
銀河の果てまで
to the edge of the galaxy,
私
I...
天才 だから 天才 だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius,
鼓動の早さも分かっちゃう
I even know the speed of your heartbeat.
あなたはなんにも知らない
You don't know a thing,
お馬鹿さん
you little fool.
天才 だから 天才 だから
Because I'm a genius, because I'm a genius,
愛など無くても分かっちゃう
I understand, even without love.
脳神経から感覚細胞
From cranial nerves to sensory cells,
意識の果てまで全部埋めてよ
fill it all up to the edge of consciousness.
ねえ あなたを
Hey, you...
“あいしてる”
"I love you."
みんなー！
Everyone!
今日は僕のお誕生日ライブに来てくれて
Thank you so much for coming
ありがとうー！
to my birthday live today!
早速一曲目「天才ロック」を歌わせていただきました！
I just performed the first song, "Ten-o Rock"!
もうね いっぱい激しく歌って踊ったので
Man, I sang and danced so intensely,
もうだいぶヘトヘトなんですけど
that I'm already pretty exhausted...
まだまだねを上げるには早すぎるので
But it's way too early to give up yet,
頑張っていきますよ！
so I'm going to keep giving it my all!
そして今回はいつもと
And this time, something a bit different...
ん？ いつもはやらないんですけど
Hmm? Well, I don't usually do this,
みんながやってて僕もやってみたいなって思ったことがあったので
but since everyone else does it, I thought I'd give it a try.
今回は実行してみました
So I've put it into action this time.
今回僕のライブにタイトルを付けさせていただきました！
I've given a title to this live performance!
今回のタイトルはですね
The title for this time is...
その名も「CATSAMA」というライブタイトルになっております！
It's called "CATSAMA"!
イェーイ！ ドンドンパフパフ！
Yay! *Trumpet sounds*!
え？
Eh?
そのままじゃんって？
"It's just as it is"?
元々猫じゃんって？
"You were already a cat"?
いいじゃん！
It's fine!
タイトル付けてみたかったんだよ
I just really wanted to give it a title.
いつもは「猫又おかゆ生誕祭2022」とか
Usually it's just "Nekomata Okayu Birthday Celebration 2022"
「2021」とかだったからさ
or "2021" and stuff like that.
やってみたかったんだよ ね！
I just wanted to try it, okay?
まあまあ この日のために
Well, anyway, for this special day,
いっぱい練習も準備もしてきたので
I've put in a lot of practice and preparation.
みんな瞬き厳禁で楽しんでいってね
So everyone, don't even blink and enjoy the show!
それではまだまだライブ続きますので
Well then, the live performance is still going,
引き続きお楽しみください！
so please continue to enjoy!
わっちゃがっちゃ熱中んちゅ
Watcha gatcha, I'm so obsessed!
しゅきしゅきで弾けたVividマインド
My vivid mind burst with "lovey-dovey" feelings.
ルーレットグッドスタートきっとゲット
A good start on the roulette, I'll surely get
一等！一等！一等！
first prize! First prize! First prize!
永久サンキューときめきKnock You
Eternal thank you, my heart throbs, I'll knock you out!
1ミリの隙間にダイビング
Diving into a 1mm gap.
ラブスタンプ全部コンプ運勢アップ
Collecting all the love stamps, my luck is up.
いいぞ！いいぞ！いいぞ！いいぞ！
Way to go! Way to go! Way to go! Way to go!
せーの！
One, two!
だって今日はゴッドメンタル
'Cause today I've got a god-like mentality!
いさましきチャレンジャー
A brave challenger.
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
Feeling just a little sentimental.
だいしきゅーだいしゅき
Emergency! I love you so much!
1 2 3 はい！
1, 2, 3, go!
まみむめめろめろ見れないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mellow, I can't look.
たちつてとてと手が触れて
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to-hands, our hands touched.
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Become an "emergency, I love you"!
もっとキュキュッキュキュッと強制ラブ
More tightly, tightly, forced love!
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート
You know, like a sea angel, a transparent heart.
demoねこの胸見透かさないで
But don't see through this heart of mine.
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Become an "emergency, I love you"!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
If it's not me, then it's all over, right?
わっちゃがっちゃ見つけつみゅ
Watcha gatcha, I found it!
しゅきしゅぎてカラフルCutieマインド
Loving you too much, my colorful, cutie mind.
ルーレットちょっとストップ一旦休止
Roulette, stop a bit, let's take a break.
いや！いや！いや！でも！
No! No! No! But!
せーの！
One, two!
だって今日は求めてる
'Cause today I'm searching
うるわしきチャレンジャー
for a beautiful challenger.
ハート描いたオートメーション
An automation that drew a heart.
だいしきゅーだいしゅき
Emergency! I love you so much!
1 2 3 はい！
1, 2, 3, go!
まみむめめろめろ...
Ma-mi-mu-me-mellow...
せーの！
Ready, set!
なにぬねこねこ
Na-ni-nu-ne-ko-ne-ko
恋のコネクト
Connect of love
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Become "daisukyuu" "daisuki"
もっとキュキュキュッて強制ラブ！
More kyu-kyu-kyu, forced love!
あのねマリオネット操られりー
You know, a marionette being controlled
でもねそれもね悪くはないね
But you know, that's not too bad either
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Become "daisukyuu" "daisuki"
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんねー！
Saying it's not me? You're finished!
フレンドリーなフリして
While pretending to be friendly
周波数を乱さないで
Don't mess with my frequency
いわくつきの魅惑のリップ
Lips with a story, alluring lips
リアルになるミラー
Mirror that becomes real
まみむめもめも目もみれないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-me-mo, can't even look you in the eye
たちつてとてと手と手が触れて
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to-te-to, hands touching hands
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Become "daisukyuu" "daisuki"
もっとキュキュキュッて強制ラブ！
More kyu-kyu-kyu, forced love!
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート
You know, a clione with a transparent heart
でもねこの胸見透かさないで
But don't see through my heart
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Become "daisukyuu" "daisuki"
アタシじゃないなんて
Saying it's not me...
終わってんねー！
You're finished!
まみむめもめも目もみれないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-me-mo, can't even look you in the eye
たちつてとてと手と手が触れて
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to-te-to, hands touching hands
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Become "daisukyuu" "daisuki"
もっとキュキュキュッて強制ラブ！
More kyu-kyu-kyu, forced love!
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート
You know, a clione with a transparent heart
でもねこの胸見透かさないで
But don't see through my heart
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Become "daisukyuu" "daisuki"
アタシじゃないなんて
Saying it's not me...
終わってんねー！
You're finished!
はぁー...
Haa...
はい！
Yes!
ということで！
And so!
あの、メスバルト、メかゆで...
Um, Mesubaru and Mekayu...
メかゆ？！
Mekayu?!
ちょっとメカブみたいになってっけど
It sounds a bit like Mekabu seaweed
なんだよ、メスバじゃないだろ別に！
What do you mean? It's not Mesubaru.
メカブでもないだろお前ら！
It's not Mekabu either!
まあまあまあ
Now, now, now
ちょっとね、今回は可愛らしい曲を
This time, we sang a cute song
スバおかで歌わせていただきましたー！
together as Suba-Oka!
いただきましたー！
Yes we did!
おかゆ、お誕生日おめでとう！
Okayu, happy birthday!
ありがとう、スバルちゃん！
Thank you, Subaru-chan!
スバルちゃんとはね、事前に僕の誕生日に
I told Subaru-chan beforehand that
この曲歌いたいから覚えておいてねって言っておいたんだよね
I wanted to sing this song on my birthday, so please learn it
そう、てかマジで「この曲歌う」みたいなの聞いたときに
Yeah, and when I heard we were going to sing this song...
マジ震え上がったよ、マジで
I was honestly trembling
なんでなんで？
Why, why?
いや「大丈夫？！」って
I was like, "Is this okay?!"
いやなんでこの曲選んだの？！
Why did you pick this song?!
いや、やっぱり僕とスバルちゃんって
Well, you and I have that
結構「戦友」みたいなそういうイメージあるじゃん
"comrades-in-arms" image, right?
まあね
I guess so
そう
Right
だから、ま、今回はちょっと正統派清楚じゃないけど
So, I thought I'd show everyone a cute,
そういうアイドルっぽい可愛らしいスバおかを
idol-like side of Suba-Oka this time,
みんなにお届けしたいなって思ったんだよ
even if it's not the traditional "pure" style
え、今までって正統派清楚じゃなかったの？
Wait, we weren't pure until now?
ま、ちょっと泥臭い...
Well, a bit unrefined...
泥臭いとか言うな！泥
Don't call us unrefined!
なんでだよ、泥！
What do you mean "muddy"!
いつも良い香りしてるだろ！
We always smell nice!
ねえ、だから今日はすごく良い香りのしそうな感じで
Hey, so today we tried to give off a really nice scent
ああー
Ah
お送りさせていただいたんですけど、どうでした？
We presented it that way, but how was it?
どうでした、皆さんも？
How was it, everyone?
スバルはね、もうずっと変な汗かきながらやってましたけどね
Subaru was breaking out in a weird sweat the whole time
確かに「だいしきゅーだいしゅき歌おう」って言ったときに
True, when I said "let's sing Daisukyuu Daisuki"...
「スバるとおかゆでこの曲歌うの？！」って言ってたもんね
You were like, "Subaru and Okayu are singing THIS song?!"
だって、もう「だいしきゅーだいしゅき」なんて
Because "Daisukyuu Daisuki" is a phrase
スバル史の中で一度も言ったことのない
I've never uttered in the history of Subaru
ね、言葉なんで
Those words
ねえ
Right?
スバルちゃんがね、必死にね
Subaru-chan worked so hard to learn it
脇汗かきながら覚えてくれた
while sweating under her arms
脇汗かいてないわ！変なこと言うな！
I wasn't sweating under my arms! Don't say weird things!
脇汗のおかげでね、こんなに素敵な...
Thanks to that sweat, we have this...
脇汗じゃない！
It's not armpit sweat!
お前も脇汗かいてるだろじゃあ！
Then you must be sweating under your arms too!
え、僕は、かいてるよ
Oh, I am
きもーい！
Gross!
きもくないよ！
It's not gross!
お誕生日、本当におめでとう！
A very happy birthday to you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃ、もう良いか？
So, are we good?
うん、もう大丈夫、ありがとう！
Yeah, all good, thank you!
大丈夫、ありがとうじゃないんだよ
Don't just say "all good, thank you"
じゃあこの後も頑張ってね！
Well, keep doing your best after this too!
はい、ありがとう！
Yes, thank you!
バイバイ、おめでとう！
Bye-bye, congrats!
はーい
Bye
鮮やかに恋してにんじゃりばんばん
Falling in love vividly, Ninjari Bang Bang
なんだかにんじゃりばんばん Bloom Bloom Bloom 花びらも舞う
Somehow Ninjari Bang Bang, bloom bloom bloom, petals are dancing too
飛んでけにんじゃりばんばん
Fly away, Ninjari Bang Bang
常識を変えたら驚きが日常に
If you change common sense, surprises become daily life
どうしてにんじゃりばんばん
Why Ninjari Bang Bang
愛してにんじゃりばんばん
Love me Ninjari Bang Bang
Ring Ring Ring 鳴らないメロディー
Ring Ring Ring, the melody that doesn't ring
ふんわり煙に巻き
Wrapped in soft smoke
空を駆けるのは
Running through the sky
にんにん　キミだけだから
Nin nin, because it's only you
見えてたものが
Things that were visible
七色に
Turn into seven colors
変わる時キミは
When they change, you are...
きっと手をのばしても
Even if you reach out your hand
触れない光のようだから
You're like a light that can't be touched
鮮やかに
Vividly
恋してにんじゃりばんばん
Falling in love Ninjari Bang Bang
なんだかにんじゃりばんばん
Somehow Ninjari Bang Bang
Bloom Bloom Bloom 花びらも舞う
Bloom Bloom Bloom, petals dance too
飛んでけにんじゃりばんばん
Fly away Ninjari Bang Bang
常識を変えたら
If we change common sense
驚きが日常に
The surprise becomes daily life
どうしてにんじゃりばんばん
Why Ninjari Bang Bang
愛してにんじゃりばんばん
Love me Ninjari Bang Bang
Ring Ring Ring 鳴らないメロディー
Ring Ring Ring, the melody that doesn't ring
ふんわり煙に巻き
Wrapped in soft smoke
空を駆けるのは
Running through the sky
にんにん　キミだけだから
Nin nin, because it's only you
どんな色にも　ならないで
Don't become any color
キミは街を染めるよ
You dye the town
広がってゆくね
It spreads out, doesn't it?
転がる巻物みたいな
Like a rolling scroll
道をつくる
Making a road
鮮やかに
Vividly
恋してにんじゃりばんばん
Falling in love Ninjari Bang Bang
なんだかにんじゃりばんばん
Somehow Ninjari Bang Bang
Bloom Bloom Bloom 花びらも舞う
Bloom Bloom Bloom, petals dance too
飛んでけにんじゃりばんばん
Fly away Ninjari Bang Bang
常識を変えたら
If we change common sense
驚きが日常に
The surprise becomes daily life
どうしてにんじゃりばんばん
Why Ninjari Bang Bang
愛してにんじゃりばんばん
Love me Ninjari Bang Bang
Ring Ring Ring 鳴らないメロディー
Ring Ring Ring, the melody that doesn't ring
ふんわり煙に巻き
Wrapped in soft smoke
空を駆けるのは
Running through the sky
にんにん　キミだけだから
Nin nin, because it's only you
恋してにんじゃりばんばん
Falling in love Ninjari Bang Bang
なんだかにんじゃりばんばん
Somehow Ninjari Bang Bang
Bloom Bloom Bloom 花びらも舞う
Bloom Bloom Bloom, petals dance too
飛んでけにんじゃりばんばん
Fly away Ninjari Bang Bang
常識を変えたら
If we change common sense
驚きが日常に
The surprise becomes daily life
どうしてにんじゃりばんばん
Why Ninjari Bang Bang
愛してにんじゃりばんばん
Love me Ninjari Bang Bang
Ring Ring Ring 鳴らないメロディー
Ring Ring Ring, the melody that doesn't ring
ふんわり煙に巻き
Wrapped in soft smoke
空を駆けるのは
Running through the sky
にんにん　キミだけだから
Nin nin, because it's only you
いろはちゃん、にんにん！
Iroha-chan, nin-nin!
あ、おかゆ先輩！
Ah, Okayu-senpai!
本日にんにん、拙者、拙者でござるよ！
Today, nin-nin, it is I, it is I!
ごめんごめん。
Sorry, sorry.
ということで、holoXの風真いろはちゃんが来てくれました！
And so, Kazama Iroha-chan from holoX is here!
うわーい！どうもこんにちはでござる。
Yay! Hello everyone.
改めまして、おかゆ先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, Okayu-senpai, happy birthday!
わーい、ありがとう！
Yay, thank you!
ねえ、実は我々ね、裏でちょこちょこ遊んだりしてるんでござるよな。
You know, we actually play together behind the scenes quite a bit.
いひひ、そうなんですよ。実はね。
Hehe, that's right. Actually, yes.
まあ、仲良くさせてもろてます。
Well, we've been getting along quite well.
ね、もろてるんでござる。そうなんです。
Yes, we are. That's right.
僕がね、ミックスとかに興味持ち始めたのも、
The reason I started getting interested in mixing and stuff is...
完全にいろはちゃんの影響というか、おかげなんで。
...entirely thanks to, or rather, the influence of Iroha-chan.
ええ、嬉しい、めちゃくちゃ嬉しいでござる。
Ehh, I'm happy, I'm so incredibly happy.
いろはちゃん、ちゅっ。
Iroha-chan, chu.
え、ちょっ、恥ずかしい、え、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ。
Wait, a bit, it's embarrassing, wait, wait, wait...
お？
Oh?
いろはちゃん、すごいさ、お足元エッチエッチじゃない？
Iroha-chan, aren't your legs like, super sexy?
え、ちょっと、おかゆ先輩！おかゆ先輩！
Wait, Okayu-senpai! Okayu-senpai!
恥ずかしい、恥ずかしい。あんまり見ないで。あ、ちょっと、見ないで。
It's embarrassing, it's embarrassing. Don't look too much. Ah, wait, don't look.
触らないで。ちょっと、だめ、だめ、だめ、だめ。
Don't touch. Wait, no, no, no, no.
ああ、もう、おかゆ先輩！
Ah, jeez, Okayu-senpai!
あ、もう本当に、もう...
Ah, geez, really...
嬉しいけど、
I'm happy, but...
うちの殿でござるよまた。
he's my lord again.
あー、ダメかー。
Ah, I see...
そうか、残念だなー。
I see, that's too bad.
うーん。
Hmm.
でもね、今日は楽しかったです！
But anyway, I had fun today!
また是非一緒に遊びましょう！
Let's definitely hang out together again!
オッケー、ありがといろはちゃん！
Okay, thanks Iroha-chan!
バイバイでござるー！
Bye-bye!
エイリアンエイリアン
Alien Alien
ゆれる街灯
Swaying streetlights
しのつく雨
Driving rain
振れる感情
Shifting emotions
感覚のテレパス
Sensory telepathy
迷子の
A lost child's
ふたりはコンタクト
two-way contact
ココロは
The heart
恋を知りました
has learned of love
タイトロープ
Tightrope
ツギハギの制服
Patched-up uniform
重度の
Severe
ディスコミュニケーション
discommunication
眼光
Glint in the eyes
赤色にキラキラ
Sparkling in red
ナニカが
Something is
起こる胸騒ぎ
causing a stir in my chest
エイリアン
Alien
わたしエイリアン
I am an alien
あなたの心を惑わせる
I'll lead your heart astray
混ざりあう宇宙の引力で
With the mixed gravity of the universe
感じてる気持ちはトキメキ
The feeling I have is a fluttering heart
エイリアン
Alien
あなたのエイリアン
Your alien
引きあう心は逃れられない
Our hearts pulling each other cannot escape
あなたに未体験あげる
I'll give you a new experience
異世界の果てまでトキメキ
Excitement to the ends of another world
スキ
I love you
点灯と消灯を繰り返している蛍光灯
A fluorescent light flickering on and off
超常な
A supernatural
混沌が静かにあなたを蝕んだ
chaos has quietly consumed you
並行な信号は特異点に混じり合った
Parallel signals merged at a singularity
創造現実妄信症　感応性本能
Creation reality blind-belief syndrome, responsive instinct
シンドローム　ひとりきり夜な夜な空想
Syndrome, fantasizing all alone night after night
描くグリモワール
Sketching out a grimoire
サーチライト　避ける浮遊機
Searchlight, an aircraft evading it
まだあなたは全てを知りたい？
Do you still want to know everything?
エイリアン
Alien
わたしエイリアン
I am an alien
あなたの心を惑わせる
I'll lead your heart astray
瞳に映らない引力に
To the gravity invisible to the eye
気づいてよわたしは
Notice me, I am...
エイリアン
Alien
あなたのエイリアン
Your alien
触れ合えば傷は二度と消えない
If we touch, the scars will never fade
降り注ぐ無数の隕石も
Even the countless falling meteors
ときめく心には届かない
Cannot reach my fluttering heart
エイリアン　ふたりはエイリアン
Alien, the two of us are aliens
高鳴る気持ちが抑えられない
I can't suppress these racing feelings
あなたは未確認生命体
You are an unidentified life form
異世界の果てまであなたが好き
I love you to the ends of another world
おかゆ先輩！
Okayu-senpai!
ぐらー！
Gura!
おかゆ先輩！
Okayu-senpai!
ぐらー！
Gura!
おかゆ先輩！
Okayu-senpai!
相思相愛！
Mutual love!
おかゆ先輩！
Okayu-senpai!
ぐらー！
Gura!
おかゆ先輩、誕生日おめでとうございます！
Okayu-senpai, happy birthday!
本日はお招きいただき、とても嬉しいです。
I'm very happy to have been invited today.
うわぁー！ぐら、来てくれてありがとう！
Whoa! Gura, thanks for coming!
僕も一緒に歌えて嬉しかったー！
I was happy to be able to sing with you too!
去年の9月のぐらちゃんのライブの時もそうだったけど、もうテンション上がりすぎてちゃんと歌えるか心配だったよ。
Just like during Gura-chan's live last September, I was so hyped I was worried if I could sing properly.
私もまたおかゆ先輩と一緒に歌えて、とっても幸せです。
I'm very happy to be able to sing with Okayu-senpai again.
Okayu is soft and huggable, I'm sure everybody knows and wants to give Okayu a big hug.
Okayu is beautiful and soft and warm and... Okayu happiness.
あー、なんかとっても嬉しいことを言ってくれてる気がする！
Ah, I feel like she's saying something really nice!
僕もぐらのこと、大好きです！
I love Gura too!
あ、あれ？
Oh, huh?
おかゆ先輩？
Okayu-senpai?
じー...
Stare...
おかゆ先輩？
Okayu-senpai?
じー...
Stare...
E-Eat... Eat...
Eh? Why... Why are you looking at me like you're about to eat dinner?
(Shriek)
あ、待って待って！
Ah, wait, wait!
触るだけだから。
I'm just going to touch you.
Really?
本当ですか？
Are you sure?
んー、んー、んー...
Hm-hm-hm...
もぐもぐ。
Munch munch.
やー！ おかゆ先輩！
Ya! Okayu-senpai!
Don't be so rough!
You have a tail, you should know how it feels!
おー、ごめんごめん。
Oh, sorry, sorry.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
おかげで元気が出たよ。
Thanks to you, I've got my energy back.
ライブもまだまだ頑張れる。
I can keep going strong for the rest of the live.
今日は本当に来てくれてありがとう。
Thank you so much for coming today.
また一緒に遊ぼうね。
Let's play together again.
はい！ また一緒に歌いたいです。
Yes! I want to sing together again.
ライブ頑張ってください！
Good luck with the live!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
雨の季節が過ぎ 澄み渡る空を眺めて独り想フ
The rainy season passes, and I think alone, gazing at the clear sky
きっと君との距離はもう あの雲のように遠くなってしまった
Surely the distance between us has already become as far as those clouds
思い出していた あの言葉
I was remembering those words
冬は良いけど夏は嫌
'Winter is fine, but I hate summer'
愛しく想う程 あなたは苦しんだ
The more I loved you, the more you suffered
そう 僕も同じ
Yes, I was the same
失う怖さと 消えない気持ち
The fear of loss and feelings that won't fade
まるで針鼠 罪のジレンマ
Like a hedgehog, the dilemma of sin
朱の季節が過ぎ 澄みきった空は冷たい風を運ぶ
The crimson season passes, and the clear sky brings a cold wind
ずっと君との日々はもう 戻るはずもない そう諦めていた
I had long given up on the days with you ever returning
戻って来たんだ 君は言う
You came back, you said
寒い夜は寄り添いたい
'I want to be close on cold nights'
寂しく凍えそうな時には 共に居た
We were together when it was lonely and freezing
そう 君と同じ
Yes, same as you
二度目の夏が近づいた
A second summer approached
このままでは過ちを繰り返すだけだろう
At this rate, we'll just repeat our mistakes
いつまで続く 君との恋
How long will this love with you last?
煩わしくなる 君の体温
Your body heat becomes bothersome
あなたの気持ち 分かってきたよ
I've come to understand your feelings
冬だけの恋 暑い夜は寝苦しい
A love only for winter; hot nights are hard to sleep through
寂しく凍えそうな時だけ 共に居た
We were together only when it was lonely and freezing
そう 君も同じ
Yes, same as you
今年も夏が近づいた
Summer approached again this year
このままでは過ちを繰り返す
At this rate, we'll repeat our mistakes
愛しく想う程 あなたは苦しんだ
The more I loved you, the more you suffered
そう 僕も同じ
Yes, I was the same
けれどいつか二人 裸で向き合える日がきっと来るはず
But surely the day will come when the two of us can face each other bare
はい！
Alright!
一発目に続いてのソロ曲、
Following the first one, my second solo song,
「夏に去りし君を想フ」でしたー。
was 'Natsu ni Sarishi Kimi wo Omou'!
この曲、僕めーーっちゃ好きで...
I rea---lly like this song...
みんなの前でいつか歌いたいなって
And I'd been thinking for a long time
ずっと思ってたの。
that I wanted to sing it in front of everyone one day.
それが今日だったんだね。
And that day was today.
えへへ。
Ehehe.
もうライブは中盤となっておりますが、
The live is already reaching its midpoint,
引き続き楽しんでいただけますか？
but are you all still having a good time?
僕らしいキャット様をまだまだ堪能していってね。
Please keep enjoying my cat-like self.
ちなみに...は...
By the way... ha...
はくしゅん！ すみません。
Achoo! Sorry.
あの、次のゲストは...
Um, the next guest is...
あの方です！
that person!
らりぱっぱらっぱぱっぱらっぱ...
Lalarippa parappa para-ppa-parappa...
純粋が駄になる世界で
In a world where purity becomes useless
らりぱっぱらっぱぱっぱらっぱ...
Lalarippa parappa para-ppa-parappa...
また来週も戦えるかな
I wonder if I can fight again next week
可愛い衣装纏って 決めポーズで光って
Donning cute outfits, shining in our signature poses
ピュアな想い魔法に変えて
Turning pure feelings into magic
みんなの平和願って 邪悪に立ち向かって
Praying for everyone's peace, facing off against evil
それを匿名はディスった
Anonymous people dissed that
「本当は〇〇なんでしょ？」
'You're actually OO, aren't you?'
「ぶっちゃけ〇〇なんでしょ？」
'To be honest, you're OO, aren't you?'
自分がそう思うから
Because I think so,
みんな〇〇であって欲しいんでしょ
you want everyone to be OO, right?
そんな手垢のついた
With such hand-stained,
よくある風評で
common rumors,
錆びつく魔法のステッキ
the magic wand rusts.
知らん 知らん
I don't know, I don't know.
正直もうやめたい
To be honest, I want to quit already.
魔法少女やめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl.
誰が敵か味方か分かんないし
I don't even know who is friend or foe,
「陰険」で「強欲」で
insidious, greedy,
「滑稽」で「軽薄」で
comical, and frivolous,
魔法が解けるチョコみたいに
like chocolate whose magic is fading.
純粋が仇になる世で
In a world where purity becomes a burden,
正直もうやめたい
To be honest, I want to quit already.
魔法少女やめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl.
もう好きな人だけ守っていたい
I just want to protect the ones I love.
だんだんと身勝手になる
Gradually becoming selfish,
魔力が煮え立つ
magical power boils over.
分量で調合したポーションがパリン！
The potion mixed with dissatisfaction... Crack!
「お前ら〇〇なんでしょ？」
"You guys are OO, aren't you?"
「性格が〇〇なんでしょ？」
"Your personality is OO, isn't it?"
脳内で〇〇しちゃうでしょう
You'll probably OO them in your head.
やり返しはナンセンス
Retaliating is nonsense.
気に病んでもスルーです
Even if it bothers you, just ignore it.
光失ったブローチ
A brooch that has lost its light,
腐る 腐る
rots, rots.
正直もうやめたい
To be honest, I want to quit already.
魔法少女やめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl.
視聴者の期待に答えるたびに
Every time I live up to the viewers' expectations,
「超人」で「清廉」で
superhuman, upright,
「潔白」で「嘘」で
innocent, and filled with lies,
固めたチョコみたいに
like chocolate hardened by them.
甘い味が病みつきでしょう
The sweet taste is addictive, isn't it?
正直もうやめたい
To be honest, I want to quit already.
魔法少女やめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl.
「やめないで」って言われんの期待してない？
Aren't you hoping they'll tell you "don't quit"?
ファンの善意の〇〇
Fans' good intentions...
心配してる〇〇
Worrying...
すべて耳を塞いでしまったの
I've blocked out everything.
正直もうやめたい
To be honest, I want to quit already.
魔法少女やめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl.
誰が敵か味方か分かんないし
I don't even know who is friend or foe,
「陰険」で「強欲」で
insidious, greedy,
「滑稽」で「軽薄」で
comical, and frivolous,
魔法が解けるチョコみたいに
like chocolate whose magic is fading.
魔法で最低な人を消そう
Let's make the worst people disappear with magic.
正直もうやめたい
To be honest, I want to quit already.
魔法少女やめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl.
自分ごと消えちゃってさようなら
Let's disappear ourselves, goodbye.
純粋が仇になる世で
In a world where purity becomes a burden,
また来週も観てくれるかな
I wonder if you'll watch again next week.
はい！どうも！
Hi! Hello!
おは椎名ー！
Ohashiina!
なんと、にじさんじさんから椎名さんが
Guess what? Shiina-san from Nijisanji
僕のお祝いに来てくれました！
came to celebrate with me!
特別やで、ほんまに。
It's special, really.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
いや、おめでとうございます。
No, no, congratulations.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ていうか、僕たち3Dで並ぶの初めてじゃない？
Actually, isn't this our first time standing together in 3D?
いや、ね！
Yeah, right!
やばいよね！
It's crazy, isn't it?
ちょっとせっかくだから写真撮ってもらおう。
Since we're here, let's get a photo taken.
ピース、ピース！イエーイ！
Peace, peace! Yay!
いや猫耳めっちゃいいなあ。
Wow, those cat ears are really nice.
ありがとう。椎名さんなら特別に触ってもいいよ。
Thank you. Since it's you, Shiina-san, I'll let you touch them.
あ、ええわ。
Ah, I'm good.
おい！なんでだい！
Hey! Why not?!
まぁいいや、来月はね、ちなみに神おかげラジオってあるんですかね？
Oh well. By the way, is there a Kamioka-ge Radio next month?
いやーどうやろなあ。
Well, I wonder.
あ！もう時間よ！
Ah! It's time!
うん、バイバイ！おめでとう！
Yeah, bye-bye! Congratulations!
語れない 眠れない
I can't talk, I can't sleep,
トロイメライ
Träumerei.
あなたの見ている正体
The true form you're looking at,
誰も読めないカルテ
the medical chart that no one can read.
不可思議 知りたいだけ
I just want to know the mystery.
嘘も現実も
Both lies and reality,
どっちも真実だったの
they were both the truth.
本当よ
It's true.
今日もひとりごと
Talking to myself again today.
なんにも無理をしないで
Without forcing anything,
わたし愛されたい
I want to be loved.
有耶無耶 サヨナラ 軽い目眩
Vague goodbyes, a slight dizziness.
あなたのいない現象
The phenomenon of you not being here,
誰も読めないカルテ
the medical chart that no one can read.
自意識 溢れ出して
My self-consciousness overflows.
鼓動世界像
Heartbeat world view
いつも噛み合わないの
We're always out of sync
痛くて
It hurts
毎夜ねがいごと
Every night, a wish
なんにも疑わないで
Without doubting anything
混ざり溶け合いたい
I want to mix and melt together
たわいない
Trifling
分からない
I don't know
理由 存在
Reason for existence
あなたと残す後悔
Regrets left behind with you
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart no one can read
不愉快 繰り返して
Unpleasantness, repeating
正しい夢は
The right dream is
かなしい声は
The sad voice is
美しい？
Beautiful?
疑わしい？
Doubtful?
羨ましいね どれ？
I'm envious, which one?
語れない
Can't talk about it
眠れない
Can't sleep
トロイメライ
Träumerei
あなたの見ている正体
The true form you're looking at
誰も読めない 眺めない カルテ
A medical chart no one reads or looks at
不可思議 知りたいだけ
I just want to know the mystery
終わらない
Not ending
ことはない
It's not the case
トロイメライ
Träumerei
あなたと跨ぐ境界
The boundary I cross with you
誰も読めない 眺めない カルテ
A medical chart no one reads or looks at
思春期 傷口胸のうち
Puberty, wounds within the heart
不可思議 知りたいだけ
I just want to know the mystery
ということで、ゲーマーズのみんなに集まってもらいました！
And with that, I've had all of Gamers gather here!
イェーイ！
Yay!
せーの！
One, two!
おかゆ、お誕生日おめでとう！
Okayu, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
っていうかさ、今回のゲーマーズの曲、なんか全然ふざけてなくない？
I mean, this Gamers song this time, isn't it like, not joking around at all?
思った！おかゆっぴ、どういうことっすか？
I thought so too! Okayu-ppi, what's the deal?
そうだそうだ！どういうことだ！
Yeah, yeah! What's the deal!
いや、どういうこともこういうことも、たまにはゲーマーズもアイドルしてもいいんじゃないかなーって思ってね。
Well, deal or no deal, I thought it might be nice for Gamers to act like idols once in a while.
なるほどね〜。
I see~.
なるほど。
I see.
だからもう今年はアイドルしてもらわなくて大丈夫です。
So you don't have to act like idols for the rest of the year.
いやいやいや！
No, no, no!
アイドルさせてよ！
Let us be idols!
させろ〜！
Let us do it!
1年に1回のノルマは達成してるんで。
You've met your once-a-year quota.
ゲーマーズのノルマあったんだ？
There was a Gamers quota?
年一だったんだ！
It was once a year!
そうです、年一でやってるんですよ、ゲーマーズも。
That's right, we do it once a year, Gamers too.
もうちょっとさせてよ、ゲーマーズもね。
Let us do it a bit more, for Gamers too.
ゲーマーズも、もう集まらなくて大丈夫です。
Gamers doesn't need to gather anymore either.
いやいやいや！
No, no, no!
おかゆ、次、次は…
Okayu, next, next is...
あ、そうだった！おかゆ、ごめん。うちは、うちらちょっと急用があってね。
Ah, that's right! Okayu, sorry. We, we have some urgent business.
ほら行こう、ミオ！
Come on, let's go, Mio!
行こう、行こう！お腹すいたし！
Let's go, let's go! I'm hungry!
バイバ〜イ！
Bye-bye!
あ、バイバ〜イ。
Ah, bye-bye.
あれ？
Huh?
行っちゃったね。
They left.
They did.
お、これはそろそろ…おかころタイムかな？
Oh, is it about time for... Okakoro time?
…だね。
...I guess so.
すろぉもぉしょん ゆっくり変わってゆく
Slow motion, slowly changing
すろぉもぉしょん
Slow motion
コンビニ寄ってお弁当買って部屋に帰ってテレビを観てた
Stopped by a convenience store, bought a bento, went back to my room, and was watching TV
クイズの答え妥協と知って夢と答えるボケを続けて
Knowing the answer to the quiz was a compromise, I kept making the joke of answering 'dream'
熱が出ちゃって薬を飲んで布団潜って目を閉じた
Got a fever, took some medicine, crawled under the covers, and closed my eyes
布団潜って　目を閉じていた
I was under the futon, eyes closed
また君の
Again, your
マヌケな顔が浮かんで
silly face comes to mind
まだ死にたくないなんてのを
Thinking about how I don't want to die yet
背負いながら
as I carry it on my back
十代、ドヤ顔で悟った人
Teens, people who understood with a smug face
二十代、恥に気づいた人
Twenties, people who noticed their shame
三十代、身の丈知った人
Thirties, people who knew their place
そのどれもが全部同じ人
All of them are the same person
汗をかいて寝巻きを着替えたら
After sweating and changing pajamas
時計の針は午前零時
the clock hands are at midnight
この曲は今一分とちょっと
This song is now a minute and a bit
あなたは今生まれて何年？
How many years since you were born?
スロウモォション　幼少から老年までコンディション
Slowmotion, condition from childhood to old age
躁鬱の乱高下で
With manic-depressive fluctuations
粘着でも不審でもない
not sticky or suspicious
ひとつ届けたいのに　こみゅにけぇしょん
Even though I want to deliver one thing, communication
狙いすぎはすべてオーディション
Aiming too much is all an audition
審美眼も老眼になって
aesthetic sense becomes presbyopic
恥の多い生涯なんて
A life full of shame is
珍しいもんじゃない
not something rare
大丈夫だよ
It's okay
それそれ、それちょれ
That's it, that's it
あどした　ありょそ　あそれ
What happened? There it is! Oh that's it!
好みに寄ってパーツいじって
Tweak parts to your liking
愛を与えるビジネス知って
know the business of giving love
過ぎた時間とこの瞬間と
Past time and this moment
残り時間が深夜混ざって
and remaining time mix at late night
咳が酷くて水飲み干して
Cough was bad, drank all the water
深呼吸してまた考えた
took a deep breath and thought again
鼻をすすって平和願って
Sniffed, wished for peace
くしゃみをしたら吹き飛ぶ諸行無常
if you sneeze, impermanence blows away
かつては無邪気に笑えた人
People who once could laugh innocently
つまずいても涙こらえた人
People who held back tears when they stumbled
だんだんくたびれた顔の人
People with gradually tired faces
そしてしわの増えた同じ人
And the same person with more wrinkles
ぬるくなった冷えピタ貼り替えて
Replace the lukewarm cooling patch
時間はまだ丑三つ時
the time is still the dead of night
この曲は残り二分とちょっと
This song has about two minutes left
あなたの寿命はあと何年？
How many years of your life are left?
グラデュエイション　入学から卒業までパーティション
Graduation, partition from entrance to graduation
水面下で喧嘩しあって
Fighting under the surface
忘れちゃいけないこと以外は
except for things not to be forgotten
どうでもよくなりゃいいのに
I wish I didn't care about anything else
イマジネイション
imagination
刺激で鈍化しちゃってレリジョン
Becoming desensitized by stimulation, religion
盲目な生活で
in a blind life
変顔のイカス遺影だって
Even a cool funeral portrait with a funny face
あざといと突っ込まれる
will be called calculating
性（さが）が問題だよ
It's a matter of nature
助けて　助けて
Help me, help me
のらりくらりのたうちまわり
Wandering and writhing
じわりじわり見覚えのない場所に
gradually to a place I don't recognize
感傷感傷に
Sentimentality, sentimentality
身をやつしても
even if I'm consumed by it
へっくしゅん　へっくしゅん
Achoo! Achoo!
くしゃみは馬鹿っぽいな
Sneezing is so stupid-looking
ぐーすぴー　ぐーすぴー
Zzz, zzz
鼻づまりの笛を
the flute of a stuffy nose
合図に
as a signal
夜が明けてく
the dawn breaks
スロウモォション
Slowmotion
スロウモォション　朝になって熱引いてコンディション
Slowmotion, morning comes, fever breaks, condition
快晴の青天井で
Under a clear blue sky
反省したり調子こいたり
reflecting or getting cocky
のんびりくたばっていく
gradually dying leisurely
スロウモォション　アイドルだって年食ってわいどしょう
Slowmotion, even idols grow old and become tabloid fodder
賑わせて骨になって
Making a fuss and turning into bones
生まれた時と最後の時が
the time of birth and the final moment
ゆっくり繋がる不思議
slowly connecting, a mystery
コンビネーション
combination
良い人と出会うためクエスチョン
A question to meet a good person
良い人ってどんなんかね
what's a good person like?
恥の多い生涯なんて...　珍しいもんじゃない
A life full of shame is... not something rare
大丈夫だよ
It's okay
ゆっくり終わってゆく
Slowly ending
スロウモォション
Slowmotion
あらためておかゆ、お誕生日おめでとう！　うぇーい！
Once again Okayu, happy birthday! Yay!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
やっぱり二人の時間もほしいなって思って。
I thought I'd like to have some time for just the two of us too.
えへへ、ころねもそう思ってた！
Ehehe, Korone thought so too!
あ、戻ってきた。
Ah, it's back.
あ、ゆっくり、ゆっくりおかころでお送りしましたけど。
Ah, we brought you Okakoro slowly, slowly.
はい、今回は「スロウモォション」という曲に二人で挑戦してみました！
Yes, this time we two challenged a song called "Slowmotion"!
いぇー、楽しかった！
Yay, it was fun!
ねえ、この曲すっごい元気になれるよね！
Hey, this song really cheers you up, doesn't it!
わかる！ これでもこの日に向けてね、いっぱい聞き込んできたからね、
I know! I've been listening to it a lot for today, so
すごい今ね、じんとしてるよ、おかゆ。
I'm really touched right now, Okayu.
よかった。嬉しい、楽しい、大好き。
I'm glad. I'm happy, having fun, and I love you.
僕も大好きだよ。
I love you too.
いつかね絶対二人で歌ってみたいなって思ってたんだよね。
I've always thought I wanted to sing it with you someday.
え、嬉しい！
Oh, I'm so happy!
っていうか僕、いつも自分のライブで好きな歌を
Actually, it makes me really happy that
ころねさんにも歌ってもらえるっていうのがすごい嬉しいんだよね。
Korone-san sings songs I like at my lives.
え、ちょっと言わせてもらっていい？
Hey, can I say something?
おかゆがさ、自分のさ、好きな曲をさ、
It makes me happy that Okayu says
歌いたいって言ってくれるのがさ、嬉しいんだおね。
she wants to sing her favorite songs.
じゃあやっぱり来年もまたころねさんと一緒に
Then I definitely want to sing various songs
いろいろ歌っていきたいね。
with Korone-san again next year.
イエーイ！ 待ってます。
Yay! I'll be waiting.
誘われなくなったら、ちょっと圧かけますので。
If I don't get invited, I'll put some pressure on you.
わかりました。じゃあ誘われなくなったらそういうことで。
Understood. So that's what'll happen if I don't invite you.
おい、やめろ！
Hey, stop it!
じゃあせっかくだね、ここころ揃ってるんで
Well, since Koka-Koro are together,
今日もちょっと一緒にピースとかしてね、
let's do some peace signs together
みんなにスクショ撮ってもらお。
and let everyone take screenshots.
そうだね。スクショタイムしよ、スクショタイム。
Right. Let's do a screenshot time.
せーの！ ピース！ イエーイ！
Ready, go! Peace! Yay!
撮れてる？ 可愛く撮ってね。
Did you get it? Take cute ones!
可愛く撮ってよ。
Take cute ones!
じゃあ、ちょっともう一枚ぐらい撮っときたいね。
Let's take one more.
もう一枚ぐらい叩く？ ポーズ何しようか？
Take another one? What pose should we do?
ポーズは...えっとね、うわああ！
The pose is... well, whoa!
ころねさん！ 待って！ どうしたの？
Korone-san! Wait! What's wrong?
あ！ 風が来る！
Ah! The wind is coming!
ころねさんのところにだけ突風が吹いてる！
There's a gust of wind blowing only on Korone-san!
ころねさん！ ころねさん！ ころねさん！
Korone-san! Korone-san! Korone-san!
ころねさん...行っちゃったね。うん。
Korone-san... she's gone. Yeah.
ふう... あ、スタッフさん。ちょっとお水もらってもいいですか？
Phew... Oh, staff-san. Can I have some water?
あ、ありがとうございます。
Oh, thank you very much.
なんか、いつも飲んでる水とはちょっと違う味がするな。ん？
Somehow, this tastes a bit different from the water I usually drink. Hmm?
は！ ふあああ！
Ha! Whoa!
展開としてはだいぶベタだけど、なんか体が光っててえ...
This is a pretty cliché development, but my body is glowing...
へえ？ や、やああ！
Eh? No, nooo!
おーけーおーけー ぼくが君の神様になってあげる
Okay, okay, I'll become your god.
おねがい おねがい しょうがないな
Please! Please! Oh well.
やぁやぁ、悩める現代の皆様
Hey, hey, all you troubled people of the modern age.
けたたましい時代の真っ只中
In the midst of a noisy era.
自分の事さえ愛せないそんな事ありませんか？
Don't you have times when you can't even love yourself?
誰かに認めてもらいたいな
I want someone to acknowledge me.
何も上手くいかずヤダヤダ
Nothing is going well, no, no.
神頼みそれなのにどこにいったら会えるの神様
Praying to god, yet where can I go to meet you, God?
どうしたの〜？ うんうん。 そっか、大変だね。
What's wrong? Yeah, yeah. I see, that's tough.
でもね〜 大丈夫！ ぼくが味方でいるからさ。
But you know, it's okay! Because I'm on your side.
生きてるだけで満点 自信持ちなよ全然
Just being alive is a perfect score. Have some confidence, really.
信じていいよ当然 君はとっても素敵だよ！
You can believe it, of course. You are very wonderful!
ありとあらゆるこの世の全てを肯定！ 肯定！
Affirm everything in this world! Affirm! Affirm!
全知全能全肯定！ それって結構神じゃない？
Omniscient, omnipotent, total affirmation! Isn't that quite god-like?
いーじゃんいーじゃんすごーいじゃん いーじゃんいーじゃんえらーいじゃん
It's good, it's good, it's great. It's good, it's good, you're praiseworthy.
そうですそうですもっと自由に生きていいんだよ全肯定
That's right, that's right, you can live more freely, total affirmation.
いーじゃんいーじゃんすごーいじゃん いーじゃんいーじゃんえらーいじゃん
It's good, it's good, it's great. It's good, it's good, you're praiseworthy.
おーけーおーけー君は最高 何度だって伝えてあげる
Okay, okay, you're the best. I'll tell you as many times as it takes.
承認欲求マウント社会 マイナス思考に自己否定
Desire for recognition, hierarchy society, negative thinking and self-denial.
誰もがみんな求め続ける自分だけにある特別感
Everyone keeps seeking that special feeling that only they have.
数値化されちゃう世知辛い時代 いいねフォロワー高評価
A harsh era where everything is quantified. Likes, followers, high ratings.
そんなの全然必要ないよ ぼくの言葉に全て委ねて
None of that is necessary at all. Entrust everything to my words.
神様も人様も何もかも信じられなくても
Even if you can't believe in gods or people or anything.
猫様を信じましょう 甘えましょう 与えましょう安心
Let's believe in the cat god, let's spoil ourselves, let's give peace of mind.
晴れの日も雨の日も支えましょう君の心を
On sunny days and rainy days, let's support your heart.
病める時泣ける時ここに来たならもう大丈夫
When you're sick, when you're crying, if you come here, it'll be okay.
Help me!
はいはい よしよし うんうん、心配しないで
Yes, yes. There, there. Yeah, yeah, don't worry.
ほらね　大丈夫！
Look, it's okay!
君もレッツ　おにぎりゃー！
You too, let's Onigirya!
いーじゃん　いーじゃん　すごいじゃん
Good, good, you're amazing
いーじゃん　いーじゃん　えらいじゃん
Good, good, you're doing great
そうです　そうです　もっと僕の
That's right, that's right, come more
側においでよ　全肯定
to my side, for total affirmation
いーじゃん　いーじゃん　すごいじゃん
Good, good, you're amazing
いーじゃん　いーじゃん　えらいじゃん
Good, good, you're doing great
おーけー　おーけー　僕は君の
OK, OK, I will be
猫様になってあげる
becoming your cat goddess
のんびりいこうよ　ばっちりピカイチ
Let's take it easy, perfectly top-notch
ファンタスティック　へっちゃらポジティブ
Fantastic, carefree and positive
まあまあ　みんな　無理しないでね
Now now, everyone, don't overdo it
めっちゃ心配だよ
I'm really worried about you
もぐもぐ　やっぱり
Mogu mogu, after all,
勇気の　よっしゃいくぞ！
courage... alright, let's go!
肯定　肯定　肯定　肯定
Affirmation, affirmation, affirmation, affirmation
全知全能　全肯定！
Omniscient, omnipotent, total affirmation!
いーじゃん　いーじゃん　すごいじゃん
Good, good, you're amazing
いーじゃん　いーじゃん　えらいじゃん
Good, good, you're doing great
さぁさぁ皆さん　ご唱和ください！
Now now, everyone, please join in!
全知全能　全肯定！
Omniscient, omnipotent, total affirmation!
いーじゃん　いーじゃん　すごいじゃん
Good, good, you're amazing
いーじゃん　いーじゃん　えらいじゃん
Good, good, you're doing great
おーけー　おーけー　新世界の
OK, OK, for the new world's
神様になってあげる
I'll become its god
楽にいこうよ
Let's take it easy
良好ルンルン
Feeling good and happy
レッツゴー　ラララ
Let's go, la la la
笑ってこ！
Let's keep smiling!
わぁ〜。なんか神様になっちゃったよ。
Wow... I somehow became a god.
あ、ということで皆さん、改めまして
Ah, so everyone, once again,
今年も僕の生誕祭に来てくれて、ありがとうございました！
thank you for coming to my birthday celebration this year!
皆さんの応援のおかげで、いつも楽しく活動できています。
Thanks to everyone's support, I'm always able to have fun with my activities.
月並みな言葉にはなるんですが、本当に感謝してます。
It might sound cliché, but I'm truly grateful.
今年も好きなこといっぱいやって、うおーって頑張りたいと思いまーす。
I want to do lots of things I love again this year and work my hardest!
おにぎりゃー、大好き。ちゅっ。へへへ。
Onigirya, I love you. Kiss. Hehehe.
えっと、あと何か言わないといけないことがあったような…
Um, I feel like there was something else I had to say...
なかったような。最近物忘れが激しくて困るな。
...or maybe not. Lately I've been so forgetful, it's a problem.
あ！そうだそうだ！
Ah! That's right, that's right!
あのね、この後猫又おかゆチャンネルにて
You see, after this, on the Nekomata Okayu channel,
「カミサマ・ネコサマ」のMVがこの後すぐ公開されます！
the MV for "Kamisama Nekosama" will be released right away!
もう動画すっごいから、みんなに絶対見てほしい。
The video is amazing, so I definitely want everyone to see it.
頼むよ！
I'm counting on you!
この動画をみんなに見せられるの、すっごく楽しみにしてたんだから。
I've been really looking forward to showing this video to everyone.
あ、あと、グッズの告知もこの後すぐあるので、
Ah, and also, there'll be a merchandise announcement right after this,
まだ帰らないでくださーい！
so please don't leave yet!
猫又おかゆ　誕生日記念2023
Nekomata Okayu Birthday Commemoration 2023
もぐもぐ〜おかゆ〜！ライブ見てくれてありがとう。すっごく楽しかった。えへ。
Mogu mogu Okayu! Thanks for watching the live. It was so much fun. Ehe.
ここからは2023年の僕のグッズの告知になるよ。イェーイ！
From here on, it's the announcement for my 2023 merchandise. Yay!
今年のグッズはお風呂に入るときやお出かけのときに使える感じにしてみました。
I made this year's goods something you can use for bath time or when going out.
ボイスも盛りだくさんです。
There are also lots of voice packs.
たくさん考えて作ったので、気合を入れて詳しく紹介していくぞ！
I put a lot of thought into making these, so I'll introduce them in detail with gusto!
まずドーン！お風呂ポスター！
First up, bam! A bath poster!
ずっと出してみたかったんだよね。
I've always wanted to release one of these.
イラストは今年も神岡ちろるママの描き下ろしです。とっても可愛い！
The illustration is once again a new drawing by Kamioka Chirol-mama. It's so cute!
これでお風呂に入るときもずっと一緒だよ。
With this, we'll be together even during bath time.
おにぎりゃー、早くお風呂一緒に入ろう。
Onigirya, let's hurry and get in the bath together.
続いてはこちら！初めてのランダムアクリルキーホルダーです。
Next is this! My first random acrylic keychains.
イラストはなもり先生の描き下ろしです。ミニマムな感じでかわちすぎる。
The illustrations are new drawings by Namori-sensei. The mini-style is just too cute.
僕自身がランダム系のグッズってわくわくするからめっちゃ大好きで、今回出してみました。
I personally love random goods because they're so exciting, so I decided to release them this time.
通常衣装、制服衣装、シャツ衣装、ポイズニャ衣装の全4種類となっています。
There are 4 types in total: standard outfit, school uniform, shirt, and Poisnya outfit.
どの僕が当たっても大事にしてほしいな。
Whichever one you get, I hope you'll treasure it.
続いてはこちら！おにぎりゃーデザインのポロシャツ！
Next up! A polo shirt with an Onigirya design!
全体ライブのときとかおにぎりゃーがたくさん集まるときにぜひ着てほしいなと思ってデザインしてみました。
I designed this hoping you'll wear it for group concerts or when many Onigirya gather together.
もちろん普段使いもしやすいかなと思います。
I think it's also easy to wear for daily use too.
襟が黒くてシュッとしてるのがおしゃれなポイントです。ぜひ着てみてね。
The black collar and slim fit are the stylish points. Please try it on.
デートに行くときはこの服で来てほしいな。
I want you to wear this when you go on a date.
そして続きましてこちら、ハンドタオル！
And following that, here's a hand towel!
こちらポロシャツとお揃いの刺繍が入っております。
This features the same embroidery as the polo shirt.
気軽に身につけられるものもいいかなと思ってタオルも出してみました。
I thought something easy to carry around would be good, so I released a towel too.
いっぱいこれでお手手をフキフキしていきましょう。
Let's use this to wipe our hands lots and lots.
拭き拭き！
Wipe wipe!
そして最後、ボイスは今回、ドドドンと録り下ろしました！
And finally, for the voices, I've recorded a whole bunch of them!
グッズを身に着けながら聴くと、グッと臨場感が出て、よりドキドキできるような内容もあります。
Some parts are even more heart-pounding and immersive if you listen while wearing the merch.
全部紹介するともう無限に説明しちゃうので、ギュッとまとめてお話しするね。
If I introduce everything, I'll be talking forever, so I'll keep it brief.
まず、激甘一押しボイス！お布団で密着添い寝ボイス！
First, my top recommendation for a sweet voice! Snuggling in bed together!
運営さんに相談しながら、ラインギリギリを攻めてみました。
I discussed it with the staff and tried to push the limits.
ふふっ。
Hehe.
バイノーラル音声なので、ぜひヘッドホンやイヤホンで堪能してみてください。
It's binaural audio, so please enjoy it with headphones or earphones.
次、お風呂上がりに膝枕されながら耳かきボイス！こちらもバイノーラルマイクで収録しました。
Next, ear-cleaning while being pillow-talked after a bath! This was also recorded with a binaural mic.
耳かき音もゴリゴリ気持ちよくなっちゃってね。
The ear-cleaning sounds are so satisfyingly crunchy.
そして最後、シチュエーションボイス3点！こちらはグッズを身に着けながら聴くと、いっぱい楽しめるかなって内容になってます。
And finally, three situation voices! These are designed to be enjoyed even more while wearing the merch.
全部あまあまです。
They're all super sweet.
キーホルダーに嫉妬するボイスは、個人的にちょっと恥ずかしい...うお、なんでもないなんでもない、なんでもないよ。
The voice about being jealous of a keychain is a bit embarrassing for me... Oh, never mind, never mind. It's nothing.
そしてそして！こちらのグッズを全部買ってくれた人には、僕の直筆サイン入りポストカードが一緒に付いてくるよ！イェーイ！
And then! For those who buy all the merch, you'll get a postcard with my handwritten signature! Yay!
一生懸命丹精込めて書かせていただきます、えへへ。
I'll put my heart and soul into writing them, hehe.
あ、ちなみに無制限となってます。お任せあれ！
Ah, by the way, it's unlimited. Leave it to me!
はい、いっぱい喋った。
Well, that was a lot of talking.
詳しくはオフィシャルサイトにも詳細書いてあるので、ぜひ見てみてね。
More details are on the official site, so please take a look.
また、今年もたくさん配信してくから、改めてよろしくお願いします。
I'll be streaming a lot again this year, so I look forward to your continued support.
いくよ、感謝、ごっかゆー！
Here we go! Gratitude, Gokkāyū!
バイバイ！んーまっ！
Bye-bye! Mwah!
えっ、なるほど。
Eh, I see.
ほー。
Ho.
ねっ、そうでしょう。
Right, isn't it?
そう。
Yeah.
お楽しみ。
Enjoy.
何かなー。
What could it be?
どうなるのかな。
How will it turn out?
そうなんだよね。
That's how it is.
おにぎり片手で。
With an onigiri in one hand.
あー。
Ah.
イェーイ！
Yay!
僕でよくなーい？うん。
Isn't it fine if it's me? Yeah.
僕にしなよ。
Choose me.
のーのー、なるなる。
No no, I see, I see.
はー、はい。
Ha, yes.
にゃっ！ほっさ！
Nya! Hossa!
あー、よいしょ。
Ah, yoisho.
見られてた。
I was being watched.
知らん、知らん。
I don't know, I don't know.
ばれてたんだよね。
I was found out.
だらだら。
Lazing around.
にゃー。
Nyaa.
行くよ。
Here we go.
完食ー！
All eaten!
にゃっ！
Nya!
もぐもぐおかゆー！
Mogumogu Okayu!
えっ、なるほど。
Eh, I see.
ほー。
Ho.
ねっ、そうでしょう。
Right, isn't it?
そう。
Yeah.
お楽しみ。
Enjoy.
何かなー。
What could it be?
どうなるのかな。
How will it turn out?
そうなんだよね。
That's how it is.
おにぎり片手で。
With an onigiri in one hand.
あー。
Ah.
イェーイ！
Yay!
僕でよくなーい？うん。
Isn't it fine if it's me? Yeah.
僕にしなよ。
Choose me.
のーのー、なるなる。
No no, I see, I see.
はー、はい。
Ha, yes.
にゃっ！ほっさ！
Nya! Hossa!
あー、よいしょ。
Ah, yoisho.
見られてた。
I was being watched.
知らん、知らん。
I don't know, I don't know.
ばれてたんだよね。
I was found out.
だらだら。
Lazing around.
にゃー。
Nyaa.
行くよ。
Here we go.
完食ー！
All eaten!
にゃっ！
Nya!